washington.org 2019-05-17

# Destination DC Privacy Policy | Washington.org

Destination DC respects your privacy and is committed to protecting the privacy of its employees, members, customers, stakeholders and other contacts. This policy describes how we collect, use, disclose and otherwise manage personal information.

**Scope**

This privacy policy applies to all personal data processed by full-time and part-time employees, volunteers when acting on behalf of Destination DC and all business processes conducted by Destination DC through our website, web forms, social media, emails and phone. It is applicable to both the Washington DC Convention and Tourism Corporation, Inc. (doing business as Destination DC), a 501(c)6 organization, and the American Experience Foundation, a 501(c)3 organization, referred together herein as “Destination DC”. 

**What information do we collect?**

Destination DC may collect the following personal data in line with the use purposes explained in a subsequent section:

  * Name and contact details
  * Date of birth
  * Online profile data/usage
  * Emergency contact information
  * Social media profile information
  * Copies of identification documents
  * Education and professional information
  * Registration and participation in Destination DC events and activities
  * Subscription preferences
  * Information about the device(s) you use
  * Information about service usage
  * Cookies
  * Authentication data
  * Location information
  * Other information you upload or provide to us

**How do we use your information?**

Destination DC uses your personal information for the following purposes:

**To process transactions.**  Destination DC uses personal information such as name, physical address, telephone number, email address and company/institution to engage in interactions with you, including contacting you about your subscription, event participation or membership.

**To provide support or other services.**  Destination DC may use your personal information to provide you with support or other services that you have requested. Destination DC may also use your personal information to respond directly to your requests for information, including registrations for newsletters, webinars or other specific requests.

**To provide information based on your needs and respond to your requests**. Destination DC may use your personal information to provide notices of new openings and service developments in the Washington, DC area.

**To provide online forums and social networks.**  Some services available on the website permit you to participate in interactive discussions, post comments, opportunities or other content to a bulletin board or exchange, or otherwise engage in networking activities. Some services are moderated; all may be accessed for technical reasons (for example, for improvements or fixes). Destination DC does not control the content that users post to these forums or social networks. You should carefully consider whether you wish to submit personal information to these forums or social networks and tailor any content you submit appropriately and in accordance with the relevant terms of use. You should also review any additional terms and conditions that may govern your use of these services, including terms related to sharing your personal information and receiving communications.

**To select content, improve quality, and facilitate website use.**  Destination DC may use your personal information, including the information gathered as a result of site navigation and electronic protocols and cookies (including third-party cookies), to help create and personalize website content, improve website quality, track marketing campaign responsiveness, evaluate page response rates, conduct usability testing and facilitate your use of the website (for example, to facilitate navigation and the login process, avoid duplicate data entry, enhance security, keep track of shopping cart additions and preserve order information between sessions).

**To serve personalized advertising to you.**  We don't share your information with advertisers without your consent. We allow advertisers to choose the characteristics of users who will see their advertisements, and we may use any of the non-personally-identifiable attributes that we have collected to select the appropriate audience for those advertisements. When you click on or otherwise interact with an advertisement, there is a possibility that the advertiser may place a cookie in your browser and that your attributes meet the criteria the advertiser selected.

**To communicate with you about a meeting, conference or event.**  We may communicate with you about a meeting, conference or event hosted or co-sponsored by Destination DC or one of our business members. This may include information about the event's content, logistics, payment, updates and additional information related to the event. Information that you provide when registering for or participating in a conference managed or co-sponsored by parties, other than or in addition to Destination DC, may be shared with those parties, and the treatment of such information is further subject to the privacy policies of those parties. Destination DC and its conference co-sponsors may contact you about the event, subsequent iterations of the event and related events. Please note that Destination DC conference, meeting or event organizers, co-sponsors, exhibitors and other third parties may directly request your personal information at their conference booths or presentations. Providing your information to them is optional, and you should review their privacy policies to address your needs and concerns about how they will treat your personal information.

**To include you in Destination DC Member Directories**. If you are an active member of Destination DC, at your request, we may include your information in the Destination DC Member Directory and in publications including the Official Visitor Guide and Event Planning Guide.

**To assist in your participation in Destination DC activities.**  Destination DC will communicate with you, if you are participating in certain Destination DC activities such as Destination DC hosted meetings and seminars. Destination DC may send you information such as newsletters related to those activities.

**To engage with third parties**. Destination DC may share your personal data with third parties in connection with services that these individuals or entities perform for or with Destination DC. These third parties are restricted from using data in any way other than to provide services for Destination DC or for the collaboration in which they and Destination DC are contractually engaged (for example, hosting a Destination DC database or engaging in data processing on Destination DC’s behalf, or mailing you information that you requested). These third parties are carefully selected by Destination DC and are obligated to keep your data secure.

**To protect Destination DC content and services.**  We may use your information to prevent potentially illegal activities and to enforce our terms and conditions. We also use a variety of technological systems to detect and address anomalous activity and to screen content to prevent abuse, such as spam. These efforts may, on occasion, result in a temporary or permanent suspension or termination of some functions for some users.

**To get feedback or input.**   To deliver services of most interest to our customers, at times, we may ask members, customers, volunteers and website visitors to provide input and feedback (for example through surveys, usability studies or focus groups).

**To protect Destination DC information assets as well as your own personal data.**  The Destination DC Information Security Program protects the confidentiality, integrity, and availability of Destination DC information assets by following a risk management approach based on policies, standards, guidelines and procedures to meet security objectives while supporting business and operational goals.

**How can you control your information?**

You can control the information we have about you and how we use it in several ways.

  * If you are a registered user, you can request to review, correct or delete the personal data that you have provided to Destination DC by contacting privacy [at] destinationdc.com
  * Use the unsubscribe method provided in our various communications

**How will you know if the Privacy Policy is changed?**

Destination DC may update its Privacy Policy. If we make any material changes, we will notify you by email if you are a registered member, customer or client of Destination DC, or by means of a notice on our website prior to the change becoming effective. We encourage you to periodically review this page for the latest information on our privacy practices.

**Technical and regulatory information**

**Logging practices**

Destination DC automatically records the Internet Protocol (IP) addresses of visitors. The IP address is a unique number assigned to every computer on the internet. Generally, an IP address changes each time you connect to the internet (it is a "dynamic" address). Note that if you have a broadband connection, depending on your circumstance, the IP address that we collect may contain information that could be deemed identifiable. This is because with some broadband connections, your IP address doesn't change (it is "static") and could be associated with your personal computer.

In addition to recording the IP addresses of users, Destination DC may also keep track of sites that users visited immediately prior to visiting washington.org and the search terms they used to find it. We keep track of the pages visited on washington.org, the amount of time spent on those pages and the searches done on them. Your searches remain confidential and anonymous. Destination DC uses this information only for statistical purposes to find out which pages users find most useful and to improve the website.

Destination DC also captures and stores information that you transmit. This may include:

  * Browser/device type/version
  * Operating system used
  * Media Access Control (MAC) address
  * Date and time of the server request
  * Volume of data transferred

**External links behavior**

Some of washington.org's pages link to other sites created and maintained by other public and/or private sector organizations. Destination DC provides these links solely for your information and convenience. When you transfer to an outside website, you are leaving the Destination DC domain, and Destination DC's information management policies no longer apply. Destination DC encourages you to read the privacy statement of each external website that you visit before you provide any personal data.

**Cookies and web beacons**

Cookies and web beacons are electronic placeholders that are placed on your device by websites to track your individual movements on that website over time. Destination DC uses both session-based cookies (which last only for the duration of the user's session) and persistent cookies (which remain on your device and provide information about the session you are in and waits for the next time you use that site again).

Cookies and web beacons provide useful information to Destination DC, enabling us to recognize repeat users, facilitate the user's access to and use of our site, allow us to track usage behavior and to balance the usage of our website on all Destination DC web servers.

Tracking cookies, third-party cookies and other technologies such as web beacons may be used to process additional information, enable non-core functionalities on washington.org and enable third-party functions (such as a social media "share" link). We may also include web beacons and other similar technology in promotional email messages to determine whether the messages have been opened.

**Do Not Track (DNT)**

The online advertising industry has self-regulatory initiatives designed to provide consumers a choice in the types of ads they may see online and to conveniently opt-out from online behavioral ads served by some or all of the companies participating in these programs. Our websites do not respond to DNT consumer browser settings.

**Collaboration with authorities**

Destination DC has appointed and mandated a privacy officer who represents the regulatory authorities inside Destination DC, and in return represents Destination DC to regulatory authorities.

The Destination DC privacy officer will ensure proper communication with the relevant regulatory authority for privacy. The privacy officer will lead investigative action, complaint handling and data breach notification. The privacy officer will also monitor regulatory changes and consult the regulatory authority where implementation of a regulatory or technological change leads to doubt.

**Transfer of information to other countries**

As a global organization, Destination DC engages in numerous international activities. In connection with the management of those activities, Destination DC may transfer information to other countries. By submitting your information to Destination DC via its website, or in connection with your interactions with Destination DC offline, you consent to such transfers and to the processing of information in other countries.

**Responses to legal requests**

Destination DC reserves the right to share your information to respond to duly authorized information requests of governmental authorities or where required by law.

**Your European Union privacy rights**

Under the General Data Protection Regulation (also known as GDPR), if you are an individual protected by the GDPR you may have certain rights as a data subject. To request information about or avail yourself of those rights, please send an email to privacy [at] destinationdc.com with "GDPR Request" in the subject line. In the email, please specifically describe the GDPR right that you are requesting assistance with. Please note, additional information may be needed prior to initiation of a request and that Destination DC reserves the right to charge a fee with respect to certain requests. Upon Destination DC’s completion of its review, you will be notified if your request has been granted or denied, or if exemptions apply.

**How do I contact you if there is an issue?**

If you have any questions or concerns about this Privacy Policy or about the use of your personal information, please feel free to contact us by email at privacy [at] destinationdc.com.

**Contact information:**

privacy [at] destinationdc.com

Destination DC  
901 7th Street NW, Suite 400  
Washington, DC 20001
